Long ago, in ancient China,
Dahulu kala, di China kuno,
the Peacocks ruled over Gongmen City.
Burung Merak menguasai Kota Gongmen.
They brought great joy and prosperity to the city
Mereka membawa kebahagiaan dan kemakmuran pada kota
for they had invented fireworks.
sebab mereka menciptakan kembang api.
But their son, Lord Shen,
Tapi putra mereka, Raja Shen,
saw darker power in the fireworks.
melihat kekuatan jahat di kembang api.
What had brought color and joy
Yang membawa warna dan kebahagiaan
could also bring darkness and destruction.
juga bisa membawa kegelapan dan kehancuran.
Shen's troubled parents consulted a soothsayer.
Orang tua Shen yang khawatir menanyakan peramal.
She foretold that if Shen continued down this dark path,
Dia meramal, bila Shen terus menjalani jalur hitam ini,
he would be defeated by a warrior of black and white.
dia akan dikalahkan pendekar hitam putih.
The young ford set out fo change his fate.
Raja muda itu pergi untuk mengubah nasibnya.
But what he did next only sealed it.
Tapi yang dia lakukan membuatnya nyata.
Shen returned to his parents full of pride.
Shen kembali ke orang tuanya dengan bangga.
But in their faces, he saw only horror.
Di wajah mereka, dia melihat rasa ngeri.
He was banished from the city forever.
Dia diusir dari kota itu selamanya.
But Shen swore revenge.
Tapi Shen bertekad dendam.
Someday he would return
Suatu hari dia akan kembali
and all of China would bow at his feet.
dan seluruh China akan menyembah di kakinya.
It's almost done, Lord Shen, but we've run out of metal.
Hampir selesai, Raja Shen, tapi logamnya hampir habis.
Search the farthest villages! Find more metal!
Cari di desa-desa terjauh! Cari logam lagi!
China will be mine.
China akan menjadi milikku.
And then the Dragon Warrior joined the Furious Five!
Lalu Pendekar Naga bergabung dengan Lima Pendekar!
And they became the most awesomest kung fu team ever!
Mereka menjadi regu kung fu terhebat!
Enough talk. Let's fight!
Cukup bicara. Mari bertarung!
- Thirty-three... - Listen, listen!
Tiga puluh tiga...! Dengar!
You can hear the Dragon Warrior training right now!
Kau bisa mendengar Pendekar Naga berlatih sekarang!
Thirty-three. Stop him!
Tiga puluh tiga. Hentikan dia!
- Thirty-four. - It's too dangerous!
Tiga puluh empat.! Berbahaya!
- Thirty-five. Stay focused. - Thirty-six!
Tiga puluh lima. Konsentrasi.! Tiga puluh enam!
- Thirty-seven! - Yeah!
Tiga puluh tujuh!!Ya!
How is he doing that with his face?
Bagaimana cara dia melakukannya?
Thirty-eight bean buns!
Tiga puluh delapan roti kacang!
Yes! New record! You monster!
Ya! Rekor baru! Kau hebat!
- Keep going! Hit 40! - He'll never hit 40.
Teruskan! Sampai 40!! Dia tak mungkin mencapai 40.
You guys wait and we'll go to 40.
Tunggu saja, pasti sampai 40.
Do it.
Lakukanlah.
No problem!
Tidak masalah!
Yeah!
Ya!
Give me a minute.
Beri aku waktu.
- He did it! - Well done, Po!
Berhasil!!Hebat, Po!
Your training has paid off.
Latihanmu berguna juga.
Master Shifu! Gotta go. See you later!
Guru Shifu! Aku harus pergi. Sampai nanti!
You'll save those for me, right?
Sisakan untukku, ya?
Flippety-do.
Melompat.
Inner peace.
Kedamaian jiwa.
Master Shifu.
Guru Shifu.
Master Shifu, what do we got?
Guru Shifu, siapa musuh kita?
Pirates? Vandals of Volcano Mountain?
Bajak laut? Perusak Gunung Berapi?
Whatever it is, I will take them down. ‘Cause I am in a mood.
Apapun itu, aku akan kalahkan. Aku sedang ingin bertempur.
I need to get something done, you know what I mean?
Aku perlu melakukan sesuatu, kau mengerti maksudku?
What are you doing?
Kau sedang apa?
One of Master Oogway's final teachings.
Salah satu ajaran terakhir Guru Oogway.
Awesome!
Hebat!
How did you do that?
Bagaimana caranya?
- Inner peace. - Inner piece. That's cool.
Kedamaian jiwa.! Kedamaian jiwa. Bagus.
- Inner piece of what? - It is the next phase of your training.
Kedamaian jiwa apa?! Ini tahap latihanmu berikutnya.
Every master must find his path to inner peace.
Setiap guru harus mencari jalan menuju kedamaian jiwa.
Some choose to meditate for 50 years in a cave just like this...
Ada yang bertapa selama 50 tahun di gua seperti ini...
.. without the slightest taste of food or water.
...tanpa makanan atau air minum.
Or?
Atau?
Some find it through pain and suffering, as I did.
Ada yang menemukannya dengan rasa sakit dan penderitaan, seperti aku.
Po, the day you were chosen as Dragon Warrior
Po, hari saat kau dipilih sebagai Pendekar Naga
was the worst day of my life.
ialah hari terburuk dalam hidupku.
By far. Nothing else came close.
Sejauh ini. Tiada yang lebih buruk.
It was the worst, most painful, mind-destroying, horrible moment...
Itulah saat terburuk, menyakitkan, merusak pikiran...
- OK. -..[ have ever experienced.
Baiklah.! ...yang pernah aku rasakan.
But once I realized the problem was not you, but within me,
Saat aku sadar, masalahnya bukan kau, tapi aku,
I found inner peace and was able to harness the flow of the universe.
aku meraih kedamaian jiwa dan memanfaatkan aliran dunia.
So that's it? I just need inner peace?
Begitu? Aku hanya butuh kedamaian jiwa?
My innards are already super, super peaceful,
Jiwaku sudah amat damai,
so alll need to do is just get this thing going.
jadi aku hanya perlu melaksanakannya.
Inner peace, you're going down.
Kedamaian dunia, kau akan tunduk.
Now show me what you were doing there with your feet.
Tunjukkanlah gaya kakimu.
I saw you do sort of a fancy foot...
Kakimu bergerak...
Po! Bandits! Approaching the Musicians Village.
Po! Para penjahat mendekati Desa Pemusik.
Danger.
Bahaya.
Tell those musicians to start playing some action music because it is on.
Minta para pemusik memainkan musik aksi, sebab kita akan bertempur.
Don't worry, Shifu, I'll master inner peace as soon as I get back.
Tenang, Shifu, aku akan belajar kedamaian jiwa.
No snack stops this time.
Tanpa berhenti untuk kudapan.
Snack stops.
Kudapan.
Wait, are you serious?
Tunggu, kau serius?
Get all the metal you can find!
Rampas semua logam yang ada!
Grab the metal!
Ambil logamnya!
Help, help, help, help. Help!
Tolong, tolong, tolong. Tolong!
That's everything! Let's get out of here.
Sudah semua! Mari pergi dari sini.
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
Wings of Justice!
Sayap Keadilan!
The Dragon Warrior!
Pendekar Naga!
A panda? That's impossible.
Seekor panda? Tak mungkin.
My fist hungers for justice.
Tinjuku lapar akan keadilan.
That was my... fist.
Itu... tinjuku.
- Get ‘em! - Come on!
Serang mereka!!Ayo!
Take that!
Rasakan!
Po! Incoming!
Po! Terimalah!
Thanks, Mantis!
Terima kasih, Belalang!
Tigress, Double Death Strike!
Macan, Serangan Kematian Ganda!
Feet of Fury!
Tendangan Dahsyat!
Tigress! Monkey!
Macan! Monyet!
Viper! Mantis!
Ular! Belalang!
Bunny! What?
Kelinci! Apa?
Oh, sorry.
Oh, maaf.
Help!
Tolong!
- Crane, go! -I'm on it!
Bangau, pergilah!) Aku tangani!
Is everyone OK?
Semuanya baik-baik saja?
That was awesome!
Itu hebat!
I got this.
Aku atasi ini.
Po!
Po!
Chew on that, tubby!
Rasakan itu, gendut!
Help.
Tolong.
- Sweetie, are you OK? - What happened?
Sayang, kau tak apa-apa?! Apa yang terjadi?
I think I saw...
Kurasa aku melihat...
I think...
Kurasa...
I gotta go.
Aku harus pergi.
Thank you. Thank you for coming to Dragon Warrior Noodles and Tofu.
Terima kasih. Terima kasih untuk datang ke Mie dan Tahu Pendekar Naga.
- More tea? Lemon sauce? - No.
Teh lagi? Saus limun?! Tidak.
If you need anything, just ask.
Bila butuh apapun, minta saja.
- Thank you. - Feet of Fury!
Terima kasih.! Tendangan Dahsyat!
The Dragon Warrior's mop. He mopped these very floors!
Kain pel Pendekar Naga. Dia mengepel lantai ini!
No touching! You'll get the mop dirty.
Jangan sentuh! Nanti pelnya kotor.
- He once waited on me. - Awesome!
Dia dulu melayani aku.Hebat!
Yeah, I have the stain to prove it. Hey, where is the Dragon Warrior?
Ya, noda ini buktinya. Hei, mana si Pendekar Naga?
He doesn't work here anymore.
Dia tak bekerja di sini lagi.
He's busy out there protecting the Valley.
Dia sibuk melindungi Lembah.
- The Dragon Warrior! - There he is.
Pendekar Naga!Itu dia.
Po!
Po!
- Here. OK. Nice kid. - The Dragon Warrior!
Ini. Baiklah. Anak yang baik.! Pendekar Naga!
- Should've told me you were coming. - Hi, Dad.
Seharusnya kau bilang bila akan pulang.!Hai, Ayah.
I would have saved you some stinky tofu.
Aku pasti akan sisakan tahu bau untukmu.
- Dad, can I talk to you? - Of course, son.
Ayah, bisa aku bicara padamu?! Tentu saja, nak.
In honor of my son, free tofu dessert for everybody!
Karena kedatangan putraku, gratis hidangan tahu untuk semuanya!
With purchases.
Dengan pembelian.
Oh, it's so good to see you, Po.
Oh, senang sekali kau datang, Po.
Have you lost weight? I can almost put my wings around you.
Beratmu berkurang? Sayapku hampir bisa memelukmu dengan sempurna.
Ah, well, maybe a little.
Ah, ya, mungkin sedikit.
Poor you, you must feel weak. Let me get you some soup.
Kasihan, kau pasti merasa lemah. Aku akan hidangkan sup.
No, that's OK, Dad. I'm not hungry.
Tidak apa-apa, Ayah. Aku tidak lapar.
Not hungry? Po, are you all right?
Tidak lapar? Po, kau baik-baik saja?
Yeah. No, I'm fine. I just...
Ya. Tidak apa-apa. Aku hanya...
Earlier today, I was fighting these bandits.
Hari ini, aku melawan para penjahat.
Nothing too dangerous. I mean, they were just, you know...
Tidak terlalu berbahaya. Mereka hanya...
- Yeah? - And then the strangest thing happened.
Ya?!Lalu ada hal aneh terjadi.
I had this crazy vision.
Aku melihat sesuatu yang aneh.
I think l saw my mom and me, as a baby.
Kurasa aku melihat ibuku dan aku, saat masih bayi.
Mom? A baby?
Ibu? Bayi?
- Dad? - What...?
Ayah?Apa...?
How do I say this?
Bagaimana cara aku mengatakannya?
Where did I come from?
Aku berasal dari mana?
Well, you see, son, baby geese come from a little egg.
Begini, nak, bayi angsa berasal dari telur kecil.
- Don't ask where the egg comes from. - Dad, that's not what I meant.
Jangan tanya asal telur itu.J Ayah, bukan itu maksudku.
I know it's not.
Aku tahu.
I think it’s time I told you something I should have told you a long time ago.
Kurasa sudah saatnya aku memberitahumu
OK.
Baiklah.
You might have been kind of a...
Kau mungkin...
..adopted.
...diadopsi.
- 1 knew it. - You knew?
Aku sudah tahu.! Kau tahu?
- Well, who told you? - No one. I mean, come on, Dad.
Siapa yang memberitahumu?! Tidak ada. Yang benar saja, Ayah.
But if you knew, why didn't you ever say anything?
Bila kau tahu, kenapa kau tak pernah bilang?
Why didn't you say anything?
Kenapa kau tak pernah bilang?
How did I get here, Dad? Where did I come from?
Bagaimana aku ada di sini, Ayah? Dari mana asalku?
Actually... you came from this.
Sebenarnya... kau datang dari ini.
It was just another day at the restaurant.
Hari itu seperti biasa di restoran.
Time to make the noodles.
Saatnya membuat mie.
! went out to the back, where my vegetables had just been delivered.
Aku ke belakang, di mana sayuranku baru diantar.
There were cabbages, turnips, radishes.
Ada kubis, lobak, radis.
Only there were no radishes.
Tapi, tak ada radis.
Just a very hungry baby panda.
Hanya bayi panda yang amat lapar.
There was no note.
Tidak ada catatan.
Of course, you could have eaten it.
Tentu, kau mungkin telah memakannya.
! waited for someone to come looking for you, but no one did.
Aku menunggu orang datang mencarimu, tapi tak ada.
! brought you inside.
Aku membawamu masuk.
Fed you.
Memberimu makan.
Gave you a bath.
Memandikanmu.
And fed you again.
Dan memberimu makan lagi.
And again.
Dan lagi.
And tried to put some pants on you.
Dan mencoba memakaikanmu celana.
And then I made a decision that would change my life forever.
Lalu aku mengambil keputusan yang mengubah hidupku selamanya.
To make my soup without radishes.
Untuk membuat supku tanpa radis.
And to raise you as my own son.
Dan membesarkanmu sebagai putraku sendiri.
Xiao Po, my little panda.
Xiao Po, panda kecilku.
And from that moment on, both my soup and my life
Sejak itu, supku dan hidupku
have been that much sweeter.
menjadi lebih manis.
And, little Po, that's the end of the story.
Dan, Po kecil, itu akhir kisahnya.
Look at me. No, don't look at me.
Lihatlah aku. Tidak, jangan lihat aku.
That's it? That can't be it. There's gotta be more, Dad!
Itu saja? Tak mungkin. Pasti lebih dari itu, Ayah!
Well, there was the time you ate all my bamboo furniture.
Kau pernah memakan semua perabot bambuku.
It was imported, too.
Itu perabot impor.
One dumpling, please, Dragon Warrior size.
Satu kue bola, ukuran Pendekar Naga.
Oh, Po, your story may not have such a happy beginning,
Oh, Po, kisahmu mungkin tak berawal bagus,
but look how it turned out.
tapi lihatlah sekarang.
You got me, you got kung fu, and you got noodles.
Kau punya aku, kung fu dan mie.
I know. I just have so many questions.
Aku tahu. Aku hanya punya banyak pertanyaan.
Like how did I ever fit in this tiny basket?
Kenapa aku pernah muat di keranjang kecil ini?
Why didn't I like pants?
Kenapa aku tidak suka pakai celana?
And who am I?
Siapakah aku?
Good. Watch your form.
Bagus. Perhatikan sikapmu.
Good.
Bagus.
Better. Elbow.
Lebih baik. Siku.
Straighten it out!
Luruskan!
Shen?
Shen?
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Selamat siang, semuanya.
Now we've got the pleasantries out of the way, please leave my house.
Kita telah saling menyapa, sekarang tolong tinggalkan rumahku.
- Your house? - Yes.
Rumahmu?'Ya.
Didn't you see the peacock on the front door?
Tidakkah kau melihat burung merak di pintu depan?
There you are, Soothsayer.
Kau di sini, peramal.
It seems your fortune-telling skills are not as good as you thought.
Kelihatannya, ramalanmu tak sebagus yang kau kira.
- We shall see, Shen. - No, you shall see, old goat.
Kita lihat saja, Shen. Tidak, kau yang melihat, kambing tua.
- Where were we? - What do you want, Shen?
Kita sampai mana?! Kau ingin apa, Shen?
What is rightfully mine. Gongmen City!
Hakku yang sah. Kota Gongmen!
Gongmen is under the stewardship of the Masters’ Council,
Gongmen dilindungi Dewan Guru,
and we will protect it. Even from you.
dan kami akan melindunginya. Juga darimu.
I'm so glad you feel that way.
Aku senang, kau merasa begitu.
Otherwise, I'd have dragged that here for nothing.
Bila tidak, aku percuma membawa barang itu.
What's in the box, Shen?
Apa isi kotak itu, Shen?
You want to see? It's a gift.
Kau ingin lihat? Itu hadiah.
It's your parting gift, in that it will part you.
Hadiah perpisahan, yang akan memisahkanmu.
Part of you here, part of you there
Sebagian di sini, sebagian di sana
and part of you way over there, staining the wall!
dan sebagian jauh di sana, mengotori dinding!
You insolent fool!
Kau si bodoh kurang ajar!
- Show-off. - That is a warning.
Sok pamer.IIni peringatan.
You are no match for our kung fu.
Kau bukan tandingan kung fu kami.
l agree.
Aku setuju.
But this is.
Tapi, ini tandingannya.
Are you familiar with the master of Gongmen City?
Kalian tahu guru Kota Gongmen?
- Master Thundering Rhino? - Yes.
Guru Badak Gemuruh?'Ya.
- Son of legendary Flying Rhino?
Putra Badak Terbang yang legendaris?) Ya.
And slayer of the Ten Thousand Serpents in the Valley of Woe?
Dan pembunuh Sepuluh Ribu Ular di Lembah Duka?
- He's dead. - Whoa.
Dia sudah mati.Wah.
That's impossible.
Itu tak mungkin.
Rhino's Horn Defense is impervious to any technique.
Pertahanan Cula Badak tak terkalahkan oleh ilmu apapun.
It was no technique. Lord Shen has created a weapon,
Bukan ilmu. Raja Shen menciptakan senjata,
one that breathes fire and spits metal.
yang menghisap api dan meludahkan logam.
Unless he is stopped, this could be the end of kung fu.
Kecuali dia dihentikan, kung fu bisa berakhir.
- But I just got kung fu! - And now you must save it.
Tapi aku baru menguasai kung fu!! Sekarang kau harus menyelamatkannya.
Go! Destroy this weapon and bring Lord Shen to justice!
Pergilah! Hancurkan senjata ini dan adili Raja Shen!
OK, here we go! Here we go!
Baik, kami pergi! Kami pergi!
Wait a second. How can I! do this?
Tunggu sebentar. Bagaimana caranya?
I mean, how can kung fu stop something that stops kung fu?
Cara kung fu menghentikan sesuatu yang menghentikan kung fu?
Remember, Dragon Warrior,
Ingatlah, Pendekar Naga,
anything is possible when you have inner peace.
semuanya mungkin bila kau memiliki kedamaian jiwa.
Inner peace. Inner peace. Inner peace.
Kedamaian jiwa. Kedamaian jiwa. Kedamaian jiwa.
Peace on.
Damai selalu.
- Oh, Po? - Peace!
Oh, Po?Damai!
Oh, Po, I got you a travel pack.
Oh, Po, aku menyiapkan bekalmu.
I packed you food for weeks. Cookies, buns, vegetables.
Aku mengemaskan makanan untuk beberapa minggu. Kue, roti, sayuran.
And I even packed all your action figures. See?
Aku juga mengemaskan boneka mainanmu. Lihat?
I don't know what those are. Never seen them before in my life.
Aku tak tahu apa itu. Aku tak pernah melihatnya.
Dad, you got scratches on my Tigress.
Ayah, kau menggores Macanku.
l also packed your paintings of our best time together,
Aku juga mengemas lukisan saat-saat terindah kita,
just in case you get lonely.
bila kau kesepian.
That's me and you making noodles. And that's me and you eating noodles.
Aku dan kau membuat mie. Aku dan kau makan mie.
And that's me giving you a piggyback ride.
Kau naik kuda-kudaan.
That cute? On second thought, I'll hang on to this one.
Lucu? Akuu pikir lagi, aku akan simpan yang ini.
- Hey, they're waiting for me. - Of course, of course.
Mereka sedang menunggu aku.! Tentu saja.
You have a job to do... far from home,
Kau harus bekerja... jauh dari rumah,
in a strange city, filled with strange people, and strange noodles,
di kota asing, penuh orang asing dan mie asing,
facing horrible danger from which you might never return!
menghadapi bahaya dan kau mungkin takkan kembali!
- Don't go, Po! - 1 gotta go.
Jangan pergi, Po!)Aku harus pergi.
I'm the Dragon Warrior. It's kind of my job to save kung fu.
Aku Pendekar Naga. Tugasku menyelamatkan kung fu.
And if I don't... what am I?
Bila tidak... apakah aku ini?
You're my son.
Kau putraku.
Right?
Benar?
- Po, it's time. - Goodbye.
Po, sudah saatnya.!Sampai nanti.
Don't worry, Mr. Ping.
Jangan khawatir, Pak Ping.
He'll be back before you can say “noodles.”
Dia akan kembali sebelum kau sempat bilang "mie."
Noodles.
Mie.
Come on, guys, let's go!
Ayo, semuanya, mari maju!
Yeah!
Ya!
Yeah...
Ya...
Yeah, yeah. Yeah...
Ya, ya. Ya...
Mama?
Mama?
Mom? Dad? Is that you?
Ibu? Ayah? Kaliankah itu?
Mom! Dad!
Ibu! Ayah!
Oh, hi. Hey, son. You're back.
Oh, hai. Hei, nak. Kau sudah kembali.
Honey, what are you doing here?
Sayang, kenapa kau di sini?
But I thought...
Kukira...
We replaced you, dear, with this lovely radish.
Kami telah menggantikanmu, sayang, dengan radis lucu ini.
- Radish? - It's quiet, polite, and, frankly,
Radis?)Dia diam, sopan, dan
does better kung fu.
kung funya lebih baik.
No. No, no, no.
Tidak. Tidak, tidak, tidak.
Wait!
Tunggu!
No.
Tidak.
Radish, radish, radish, radish.
Radis, radis, radis, radis.
Inner pea...
Kedamaian ji...
Pea...
Ji...
Inner peace.
Kedamaian jiwa.
Inner peace! Inner peace! Inner peace! Inner peace! Inner peace...!
Kedamaian jiwa! Kedamaian jiwa! Kedamaian jiwa! Kedamaian jiwa...!
I'm... training.
Aku sedang... berlatih.
The mast is not a worthy opponent.
Tiang itu bukan lawan yang sepadan.
- 1am ready. - OK.
Aku siap.!Baiklah.
So serious.
Serius sekali.
I think I prefer the mast.
Aku lebih suka melawan tiang.
Apologies. I used to punch the ironwood trees by the palace to train.
Maaf. Aku dulu sering berlatih memukuli pohon kayu ulin di istana.
Now I feel nothing.
Kini aku tak merasa apapun.
That's severely cool.
Mengagumkan sekali.
Again!
Ulangi!
So, this punching ironwood trees, how long did you have to do that?
Berapa lama kau memukuli pohon kayu ulin?
- Twenty years. - Oh, 20, 20 years.
Dua puluh tahun.! Oh, 20, 20 tahun.
Is there any, you know, faster way?
Adakah cara yang lebih cepat?
You know, until you, you know, don't feel anything?
Sampai kau tak merasa apapun?
No. Besides...
Tidak. Lagipula...
...[ don't think hard style is your thing.
...kurasa kau tak suka gaya yang keras.
Po, why are you really out here?
Po, kenapa kau di sini?
I just found out that my dad isn't really my dad.
Aku baru tahu, ayahku bukan ayah kandungku.
Your dad? The goose.
Ayahmu? Angsa itu.
That must have been quite a shock.
Pasti mengejutkan.
Yeah.
Ya.
- And this bothers you? - Are you kidding me?
Ini mengganggumu?! Kau bercanda?
We're warriors, right? Nerves of steel.
Kita pendekar, bukan? Nyali kita seperti baja.
Souls of platinum.
Jiwa seperti platina.
Like you.
Sepertimu.
So hard-core, you don't feel anything.
Begitu tangguh, sampai tak merasa apapun.
- 1 was... - So, what are you guys talking about?
Aku... Kalian membicarakan apa?
Nothing. Nothing.
Tidak penting.
Po's having daddy issues.
Po mengalami masalah dengan ayah.
I'm so lucky. I don't have any problems with my dad.
Aku beruntung. Aku tak bermasalah dengan ayahku.
Maybe it's because Mom ate his head before I was born.
Mungkin sebab Ibu memakan kepalanya sebelum aku lahir.
- 1 don't know. - Mantis, this isn't about you.
Aku tak tahu.! Belalang, ini bukan tentang kau.
Po is the one freaking out.
Po yang sedang gelisah.
-I'm not freaking out. - Po.
Aku tidak gelisah.JPo.
- I'm freaking in. - Po!
Aku takut.JPo!
- What? - We're here.
Apa?Kita telah tiba.
Gongmen City.
Kota Gongmen.
My father's throne.
Takhta ayahku.
He used to let me play here beside him,
Dia dulu membiarkan aku bermain di sampingnya,
promising someday, this throne would be mine.
berjanji, suatu hari, takhta ini akan jadi milikku.
A little to the left.
Sedikit ke kiri.
Oh, but it's so heavy, Master!
Oh, berat sekali, Tuan!
Thirty years I've waited for this moment.
Aku sudah menunggu 30 tahun untuk saat ini.
Everything must be exactly how I envisioned it.
Semuanya harus persis impianku.
And I envisioned it a little to the left.
Aku ingin letaknya sedikit ke kiri.
Perfect!
Sempurna!
With the weapon by my Si... A little bit more.
Dengan senjata ini di samping... Sedikit lagi.
With the weapon by my side, all of China will bow before me.
Dengan senjata ini di sampingku, seluruh China akan bersujud padaku.
We move out in three days,
Kita bergerak tiga hari lagi,
when the moon is full and the tide is high.
saat bulan purnama dan laut pasang.
Now, you old goat, why don't you tell me my...
Sekarang, kambing tua, beritahulah...
Fortune?
Keberuntunganmu?
Future. I was going to say future.
Masa depanku. Maksudku, masa depan.
Look into your bowl and tell me what glory awaits.
Lihat ke mangkukmu dan katakan, kejayaan apa yang menantiku.
If you continue on your current path...
Bila kau terus melangkah...
. you will find yourself at the bottom of the stairs.
..kau akan sampai di bawah tangga.
I see...
Aku melihat...
I see pain... and anger.
Aku melihat rasa sakit... dan kemarahan.
How dare you! That is the finest silk in the province!
Beraninya kau! Itu sutera terbaik di provinsi ini!
Followed by denial.
Beserta penyangkalan.
This is not fortune-telling. You're just saying
Ini bukan ramalan. Kau hanya bilang
- what's happening right... - Now?
apa yang terjadi sekarang...Ini?
The most important time is now.
Saat terpenting ialah sekarang.
But if you really want to see the future...
Tapi bila kau sungguh ingin melihat masa depan...
Oh, what do you see?
Oh, apa yang kau lihat?
A peacock...
Seekor burung merak...
.. iS defeated by a warrior of black and white.
...dikalahkan pendekar hitam dan putih.
Nothing has changed.
Tiada yang berubah.
That's impossible, and you know it.
Itu tak mungkin, dan kau tahu itu.
It is not impossible, and he knows it.
Bukan tak mungkin, dan dia tahu itu.
Who?
Siapa?
- Lord Shen! I saw a panda! - A panda?
Raja Shen! Aku melihat panda!Panda?
A kung fu warrior. It fought like a demon!
Pendekar kung fu. Bertarung seperti setan!
Big and furry.
Besar dan berbulu.
Soft and squishy. Kind of plush and cuddly.
Lembut dan empuk. Halus dan enak dipeluk.
There are no more pandas.
Tidak ada panda lagi.
Even with his poor eyesight, he can see the truth.
Bahkan dengan penglihatan buruknya, dia bisa melihat yang benar.
Why is it that you cannot?
Kenapa kau tidak bisa?
Find this panda and bring him to me!
Cari panda ini dan bawa kepadaku!
Yes, sir!
Ya, tuan!
One panda lives. That does not make you right.
Satu panda hidup. Bukan berarti kau benar.
You're right. Being right makes me right.
Kau benar. Menjadi benar membuatku benar.
Then I will kill him and make you wrong.
Aku akan membunuhnya dan membuktikan, kau salah.
Will you stop that!
Hentikan itu!
That must be Shen's palace on the other side of the city.
Itu pasti istana Shen di sisi lain kota ini.
Great. We'll march into the tower and proclaim,
Bagus. Kita menuju menara itu dan menyatakan,
“We are the Dragon Warrior and the Furious Five,
“Kami Pendekar Naga dan Lima Pendekar Terganas,
and we are here to bring you to justice!"
dan kami hadir untuk mengadilimu!"
What are you doing? This place is crawling with wolves.
Kau sedang apa? Tempat ini penuh serigala.
Hey, isn't that the guy who hammered you in the face?
Hei, bukankah dia yang menonjok wajahmu?
I do not like that guy.
Aku tidak suka dia.
We need to get to that tower without being spotted by those wolves.
Kita harus ke menara tanpa diketahui serigala.
Got it. Stealth mode.
Mengerti. Gaya siluman.
- Get out of the way! - Foiled again.
Minggir!!Gagal lagi.
Now, where'd those noodles go?
Di mana mie itu?
Hello. I couldn't help but...
Halo. Aku tak bisa...
Yeah, OK. Anyway, where was I?
Baiklah. Sampai di mana?
- Where's Po? - How can we lose a guy that big?
Mana Po?! Kenapa panda sebesar itu bisa hilang?
OK.
Baiklah.
Guys! Guys?
Teman! Teman?
- Hey, Po. - What? Sorry.
Hei, Po.JApa? Maaf.
So that was stealth mode, huh?
Itu gaya siluman, ya?
To be honest, not one of my stronger modes.
Sejujurnya, bukan gayaku yang terhebat.
...gold in there, come on!
...emas di sana, ayo!
This rice is raw!
Nasi ini mentah!
You stole all my metal pots for Lord Shen!
Kau mencuri semua panci logamku untuk Raja Shen!
Either you cook my rice, or I cook you!
Tanak nasiku, atau aku masak kau!
- My apologies, but... - Po, do something.
Maaf, tapi...! Po, lakukan sesuatu.
How am I supposed to help her cook rice without getting caught?
Bagaimana caranya masak beras tanpa ketahuan?
- Wait, I have a better idea. -...two...
Tunggu, aku punya ide bagus.! ...dua...
one.
...Satu.
- Hey.
Hei.JHei.
We're here to liberate the city and bring Shen to justice.
Kami akan membebaskan kota dan mengadili Shen.
- You will need help. - Thank you, brave sheep,
Kalian perlu bantuan.! Terima kasih, domba pemberani,
but it's too dangerous. I can't let you.
tapi terlalu berbahaya. Tak usah.
Oh, no, not me. It's not safe to speak here.
Oh, bukan aku. Tidak aman bicara di sini.
Right.
Benar.
I'm talking about Masters Ox and Croc.
Maksudku, Guru Lembu dan Buaya.
They're in Gongmen Jail on Black Dragon Alley.
Mereka di Penjara Gongmen di Gang Naga Hitam.
What? They're still alive?
Apa? Mereka masih hidup?
They must be in that jail gathering intelligence,
Mereka pasti di penjara mengumpulkan data,
hatching a plot to use their awesomeness to defeat the weapon!
berencana untuk mengalahkan senjata itu!
OK, let's go!
Baiklah, mari pergi!
- Thanks, sheep. - Hey! Stop that costume!
Terima kasih, domba.! Hei! Hentikan kostum itu!
- Hold it right there! - Get them!
Berhenti!! Tangkap mereka!
- Sorry!
Tangkap mereka!Maaf!
Take that!
Rasakan itu!
- Keep going! - Faster!
Terus maju!) Lebih cepat!
Hey, stop!
Hei, berhenti!
- Look out! Watch it! - Sorry!
Awas! Hati-hati!Maaf!
Surround him.
Kepung dia.
Now!
Sekarang!
Gotcha!
Mati kau!
What? Where'd he go?
Apa? Kemana perginya?
- Spread out! Search everywhere! - What about over there?
Menyebar! Cari di segala penjuru!!Di situ?
-Is “there” a part of "everywhere"? - I... [guess.
Apakah "situ" termasuk “segala penjuru"?Ya... kurasa.
Then search there!
Maka carilah di situ!
They must be close. I can feel a kung fu chill riding up my spine.
Mereka dekat. Aku merasakan dingin kung fu menjalar di tulang belakang.
Sorry, Po. It's just me.
Maaf, Po. Itu aku.
Look. Gongmen Jail.
Lihat. Penjara Gongmen.
Aw, it's cute.
Ah, imutnya.
Cute, huh?
Imut, ya?
Nice work, Po.
Bagus, Po.
At the first sign of trouble, I'll give you a signal.
Bila terlihat bahaya, aku akan beri aba-aba.
- You mean like Crane does? - Yeah.
Maksudmu, seperti Bangau?!Ya.
Excuse me, when have I ever made that noise?
Permisi, kapan aku pernah bersuara begitu?
Master Ox! Master!
Guru Lembu! Guru!
The ferocious Master Croc!
Guru Buaya yang ganas!
And Master Storming Ox.
Dan Guru Lembu Garang.
I can't believe we're rescuing actual legends of kung fu.
Sulit dipercaya, kita menyelamatkan legenda kung fu.
We're gonna free you from those bonds of injustice. No problem.
Kami lepaskan kalian dari ketidakadilan.
Gotta be a key around here. No, they wouldn't leave a key around here.
Pasti ada kunci di sini. Tak mungkin kunci ditinggalkan.
Oh, good! You found it. Come on, you guys! Yeah!
Oh, bagus! Kau menemukannya. Ayo, semuanya! Ya!
We're coming for you, Shen!
Kami menuju tempatmu, Shen!
Guys, are we going or not? Do you want to meet us there later?
Kita pergi atau tidak? Kalian ingin menyusul?
I mean, you do want to take back your city, right?
Kalian mau merebut kembali kota, bukan?
Of course we do.
Tentu saja.
But if we stand up to Shen, he will turn the weapon on the city.
Tapi bila kami menantang Shen, dia akan menghancurkan kota.
Listen to yourself. You're protecting Gongmen City
Yang benar saja. Melindungi Kota Gongmen
by not protecting Gongmen City?
tanpa melindungi Kota Gongmen?
- If we all fight together... - Then the weapon would kill everyone.
Bila kita berjuang bersama...! Senjata itu akan membunuh semuanya.
Oh, would it? Then we use... a sneak attack!
Oh, sungguhkah? Kita gunakan... serangan tiba-tiba!
- We get inside and then... - And then you will be stopped...
Kita masuk, lalu...! Lalu kau akan dihentikan...
...by the unstoppable weapon.
...Oleh senjata tak terkalahkan.
Nothing's unstoppable except for me when I'm stopping you
Tiada yang tak terkalahkan kecuali saat aku bilang,
from telling me something's unstoppable!
berhenti bilang begitu!
Master Ox, I'm not letting you stay in this cell.
Guru Lembu, aku tak mengizinkanmu tinggal di penjara.
I'd like to see you get me out!
Coba saja keluarkan aku!
You guys see that? It's called being awesome.
Kalian lihat itu? Itu namanya hebat.
Come on! Whatever happened to being heroes?
Ayo! Mana sifat pahlawanmu?
The only hero in this town is a dead one!
Pahlawan di kota ini sudah mati!
Like I said, you are not getting me out of this cell!
Seperti aku bilang, kau takkan keluarkan aku dari penjara!
Yes!
Ya!
All right, let's go!
Baiklah, mari pergi!
I get the top bunk.
Tempat tidurku yang atas.
It's time to surrender, panda. Kung fu is dead.
Saatnya menyerah, panda. Kung fu sudah mati.
L..
Aku...
You...
Kalian...
Kung fu is dead? Fine!
Kung fu sudah mati? Baiklah!
You stay in your prison of fear with bars made of hopelessness.
Kalian tinggal di penjara ketakutan dengan jeruji keputusasaan.
And all you get are three square meals a day of shame!
Hanya dengan tiga santapan penuh cela sehari!
With despair for dessert.
Dengan pencuci mulut tanpa harapan.
We'll take on Shen and prove to all those who are hungry
Kami akan hadapi Shen dan buktikan pada semua yang lapar
for justice and honor that kung fu still lives!
akan keadilan dan kehormatan, kung fu masih hidup!
Yeah!
Ya!
Monkey?!
Monyet?!
You! You're mine!
Kau! Kau milikku!
I'll tell you what's gonna be yours!
Aku beritahu apa milikmu!
My fist in your plush, cuddly, super-soft face!
Tinjuku di wajahmu yang lembut, empuk dan enak dipeluk!
Get him!
Tangkap dia!
- Get me out of here! - Yes, sir!
Bawa aku keluar!) Ya, tuan!
Stop him!
Hentikan dia!
Faster!
Lebih cepat!
Yeah! Go, go!
Ya! Cepat, cepat!
- Lose him! - Yes, sir!
Tinggalkan dia!! Ya, tuan!
- Viper! - Hang on!
Ular! Bertahanlah!
- What? - Watch out!
Apa?!Awas!
Uncool! Very uncool!
Curang! Amat curang!
Try this!
Coba ini!
Guys, guys, guys!
Aduh, aduh, aduh!
Maybe something smaller!
Mungkin sesuatu yang kecil!
No, no! Oh, no, no.
Tidak, tidak! Oh, tidak, tidak.
Cute bunnies, off the face. Excuse me! OK, pardon me!
Kelinci lucu, minggir dari wajahku. Permisi!
Fire!
Api!
We've lost them.
Mereka menghilang.
Again! Again!
Lagi! Lagi!
Crane, catch!
Bangau, tangkap!
Gotcha!
Kena!
Guys, guys, guys, guys, give me a shove!
Kawan-kawan, dorong aku!
Mantis, now!
Belalang, sekarang!
Is that all you got? It feels like I'm fighting a big old fluffy cloud!
Begitu saja dayamu? Serasa melawan awan besar yang empuk!
Well, this cloud is about to bring the thunder!
Awan ini akan menghasilkan petir!
Your turn!
Giliranmu!
Why... are... there... so... many... signs?!
Kenapa... banyak... sekali... papan?!
Come here! Alaka-squasho!
Kemari! Rasakan ini!
Yes! Taste the defeat!
Ya! Rasakan kekalahanmu!
Let me tell you something.
Dengarkan ini.
Next time you mess with a panda, you better bring a whole a...
Lain kali kau melawan panda, sebaiknya kau bawa...
Guess nobody told you,
Kurasa kau belum diberitahu,
if you mess with the wolf, you get the fangs.
bila kau melawan serigala, kau merasakan taringnya.
I've hit you twice. What are you going to do now?
Aku sudah memukulmu dua kali. Mau bagaimana sekarang?
We surrender!
Kami menyerah!
You can chain my body, but you will never chain my... warrior spirit.
Kau bisa merantai tubuhku, tapi tak... semangat pendekarku.
- Hey, don't forget the little guy. - Did you just call...?
Hei, jangan lupa si kecil ini...! Kau menyebut...?
- Po, what are you doing? - Trust me. I got a pl...
Po, kau sedang apa?! Percayalah padaku. Aku punya ren...
No way. Eight-point acupressure cuffs?
Yang benar saja. Borgol 8 titik totokan?
Just like the ones that held Tai Lung. The more you move, the tighter they get.
Persis seperti borgol Tai Lung. Makin banyak bergerak, makin erat.
These are the best cuffs!
Ini borgol terbaik!
Greetings, panda. At last we meet!
Salam, panda. Akhirnya kita bertemu!
No, no, no...
Tidak, tidak, tidak...
We meet at last! Yes, that's it.
Kita bertemu juga! Ya, begitu.
Greetings, panda. We meet at...
Salam, panda. Kita bertemu...
- You are afraid for a reason. - 1am not afraid.
Kau takut sebab suatu alasan.! Aku tak takut.
He is coming to me in chains.
Dia akan datang dengan diborgol.
- If anyone should be afraid, it's... - You.
Bila ada yang takut, ialah...!Kau.
Don't even think about it.
Tak masuk akal.
I hope this turns out better than your plan to cook rice in your stomach
Aku harap akan lebih baik dari rencanamu memasak nasi di perut
by eating it raw and then drinking boiling water.
dengan memakannya mentah, lalu minum air mendidih.
This plan's nothing like that plan.
Rencana ini berbeda.
- How? - ‘Cause this one's going to work.
Apa bedanya?! Yang ini akan berhasil.
Keep moving.
Terus maju.
Ah, my old enemy...
Ah, musuh lamaku...
.. Stairs.
...tangga.
Thanks for carrying me those last few flights. OK.
Terima kasih untuk menggendong aku naik tangga. Baiklah.
I threw up a little bit on the third floor.
Aku muntah sedikit di lantai tiga.
Someone might want to clean that up.
Mungkin harus dibersihkan.
Is there some sort of evil janitor or something?
Ada pembersih iblis di sini?
Greetings, panda.
Salam, panda.
- We meet at... - Hey, how you doing?
Kita bertemu...! Hei, apa kabar?
Hey.
Hei.
You've grown up bigger than I thought.
Kau tumbuh lebih besar dari yang aku kira.
Hey... enough with the poking around.
Hei... jangan menyentuh aku.
Strong. Healthy.
Kuat. Sehat.
Look, I don't know who you are, but please stand aside, sir.
Dengar, aku tak tahu siapa kau, tapi mohon minggir, pak.
- That's a lady. - Oh! Sorry.
Dia seorang wanita. Oh! Maaf.
The beard threw me. It's kind of misleading.
Aku melihat jenggot. Jenggot itu menipu.
- False advertising. - Enough of this nonsense!
Salah iklan.! Omong kosong ini sudah cukup!
Bring the prisoners to me.
Bawa para tahanan ke hadapanku.
Sorry, ma'am. Get ready, guys.
Maaf, ibu. Bersiaplah, semuanya.
Keep your eyes peeled for the... weapon!
Awasilah... senjata itu!
Sparrow kick!
Tendangan burung gereja!
We did it! I just kung fu-ed it! Did you guys see that? I was all like...
Berhasil! Baru aku kung fu! Kalian melihatnya? Aku lakukan...
Do you actually believe this is the warrior destined to defeat me?
Kau percaya, ini pendekar yang ditakdirkan mengalahkanku?
I do not. I know he is.
Aku tidak. Aku tahu, dialah orangnya.
Oh, look at him. A lifetime to plot his revenge
Oh, lihatlah dia. Sepanjang hidup dia merencanakan balas dendam
- and he comes to me on his knees. - What? A lifetime?
dan dia datang berlutut.! Apa? Sepanjang hidup?
I did not have a lifetime.
Tidak selama itu.
We only heard about Master Rhino a few days ago,
Kami tahu akan Guru Badak beberapa hari lalu,
- and we came to avenge him! - You've come to avenge nothing else?
dan kami datang membalas dendam!) Kalian tak membalas hal lain?
Well, yeah. All the pots and pans that you stole.
Ya. Semua panci dan penggorengan yang kau rampas.
- I'm gonna want those back. - Nothing else?
Kembalikan semuanya.! Tidak ada yang lain?
You probably did some other evil stuff along the way. I don't know.
Mungkin kau melakukan hal jahat lain. Aku tak tahu.
- What else did you do? - You don't know?
Kau melakukan apa lagi?! Kau tak tahu?
Know what? What's so funny?
Tahu apa? Apa yang lucu?
The very thing that you clearly do not know!
Hal yang jelas kau tak tahu!
OK, enough of these riddles! Would you guys spill the beans?
Cukup sudah tebak-tebakannya! Bisa beritahu saja?
First, we come in and the weapon is tiny. Surprise, it's big.
Kami datang, senjatanya kecil. Tapi, sebenarnya besar.
And then the lady over here, I think it’s a guy, ‘cause he's got...
Wanita itu, kukira dia pria, sebab dia punya...
The only reason you are still alive
Kau masih hidup
is that I find your stupidity mildly amusing.
karena kebodohanmu menghibur aku.
Well, thank you. But I find your evilness extremely annoying.
Terima kasih. Tapi kejahatanmu amat mengganggu aku.
Who do you think you are, panda?
Kau pikir, kau siapa, panda?
Who do you think I am, peacock?
Kau pikir, aku siapa, burung merak?
Why are we laughing?
Kenapa kita tertawa?
Take aim.
Bidik.
Fire.
Tembak.
Well, light the... thing!
Nyalakan... sumbunya!
I did!
Sudah!
Fear the bug!
Awas serangga itu!
Get the weapon!
Raih senjatanya!
Tigress!
Macan!
You... You were there.
Kau... Kau dulu di sana.
Yes. Yes, I was.
Ya. Ya, memang.
- You just let Shen get away! - At least we destroyed the weapon.
Kau membiarkan Shen kabur!! Setidaknya kita hancurkan senjatanya.
Fire!
Tembak!
Oh. No, he’s got way more.
Oh. Tidak, dia masih punya banyak.
- My wing! - Help, Po!
Sayapku!Tolong, Po!
Coming!
Segera datang!
- Watch out! - Po!
Awas!iPo!
- Help me up! - No. Get him down.
Naikkan aku! Tidak. Turunkan dia.
Use the ropes.
Gunakan tambang.
Run, run, little panda!
Lari, lari, panda kecil!
- Po, come on. We need you to focus! - 1 got it, I got it!
Po, ayolah. Kau harus pusatkan perhatian!!Sudah, sudah!
Bring it down!
Hancurkan!
- We're trapped! - This way!
Kita terjebak!Lewat sini!
Goodbye!
Sampai nanti!
Fire!
Tembak!
Get back!
Mundur!
The only way out is up.
Cara keluar ialah ke atas.
What?
Apa?
Follow me! Come on!
Ikuti aku! Ayo!
Where are they going?
Mereka ke mana?
- To the top! - Come on! Keep going!
Ke puncak!) Ayo! Teruskan!
Here we go!
Ini saatnya!
- You idiot! - My nose!
Kau bodoh!)Hidungku!
Call in the wolves! All of them! I want them ready to move!
Panggil serigala! Semuanya! Siapkan mereka untuk menyerbu!
The Year of the Peacock begins now!
Tahun Burung Merak dimulai sekarang!
Right now? ‘Cause it's the middle of the year,
Sekarang? Ini pertengahan tahun,
so you'd only get like a half of the Year of the Peacock.
jadi Tahun Burung Merak hanya setengah tahun.
And this is the Year, of course, of the Peacock.
Tahun ini, tentu saja, Tahun Burung Merak.
Happy New Year, sir.
Selamat Tahun Baru, tuan.
Get the wolves ready. We're loading the ships now.
Siagakan para serigala. Kita siapkan kapal sekarang.
Now!
Sekarang!
Now, now, now, now, now!
Sekarang, sekarang, sekarang!
Move! Move, move, move, move!
Maju! Maju, maju, maju!
This way.
Kemari.
Let's go.
Mari pergi.
Oh, you!
Oh, kalian?
What did you do? It's chaos up there.
Apa yang kalian lakukan? Ribut sekali.
What happened to stopping Shen?
Bagaimana dengan melawan Shen?
Yeah.
Ya.
Guys, come on. Give me a little credit.
Yang benar saja. Aku tidak separah itu.
I meant for him to get away.
Aku ingin dia kabur.
‘Cause... it was a trick. It was a plot.
Sebab... itu muslihat. Itu rencana.
I was thinking... I'll figure out his plot more.
Aku pikir... Aku akan tahu rencananya.
That makes no sense.
Itu tak masuk akal.
What do you mean? Sure it does.
Apa maksudmu? Itu masuk akal.
Po, the truth. You had Shen. What happened?
Po, jujurlah. Kau sudah mengalahkan Shen. Kenapa?
What are you talking about? I don't know what you're talking about.
Apa maksud kalian? Aku tak mengerti.
I... Yeah... OK, he caught me off guard.
Aku... Ya... Baiklah, dia mengagetkan aku.
The truth.
Sejujurnya.
Fine. They will keep you far from danger.
Baiklah. Mereka akan melindungimu jauh dari bahaya.
- Real far. - What?
Jauh sekali.!Apa?
You're staying here.
Kau tinggal di sini.
Wait! I have to go ba...
Tunggu! Aku harus kem...
You're staying here!
Kau tinggal di sini!
I'm going. And you can't stop me.
Aku ikut. Kau tak bisa menghentikan aku.
OK. I wasn't ready that time.
Baiklah. Aku belum siap tadi.
Guys? Don't.
Kalian berdua? Jangan.
Ready.
Siap.
Look!
Lihat!
Stay down.
Tiaraplah.
-l have to get to him. - Then tell me why!
Aku harus mengalahkan dia.! Beritahu kenapa!
He was there! OK?
Dia ada di sana! Mengerti?
The peacock was there the last time I saw my parents.
Burung merak itu di sana terakhir kali aku melihat orangtuaku.
He knows what happened. Where I came from.
Dia tahu apa yang terjadi. Dari mana asalku.
Who I am.
Siapakah aku.
Look, I'm going.
Aku akan pergi.
I have to know.
Aku harus tahu.
The hard core can't understand.
Si tangguh takkan mengerti.
Tigress, no!
Macan, jangan!
The hard core do understand.
Si tangguh mengerti.
But I can't watch my friend be killed.
Tapi aku tak bisa melihat temanku dibunuh.
- We're going. - Maybe you can't watch me be killed?
Kita pergi.! Kau tak bisa melihat aku dibunuh?
- Stop being a wimp. - And she's back.
Jangan jadi pengecut. Dia sudah kembali normal.
- No. - Don't worry, kid.
Tidak.! Jangan khawatir, nak.
You're better off here.
Kau lebih baik di sini.
You were wrong, Soothsayer. We sail to victory tonight.
Kau salah, peramal. Kita akan menang malam ini.
Your magic panda is clearly a fool.
Panda ajaibmu memang bodoh.
Are you certain it is the panda who is a fool?
Kau yakin, panda itu yang bodoh?
You just destroyed your ancestral home, Shen.
Kau baru menghancurkan rumah leluhurmu, Shen.
A trivial sacrifice... when all of China is my reward.
Pengorbanan sepele... saat seluruh China adalah imbalannya.
Then will you finally be satisfied?
Kapan kau akan merasa puas?
Will the subjugation of the whole world finally make you feel better?
Kau akan puas bila seluruh dunia takluk padamu?
It's a start. l might also convert the basement into a dungeon.
Bisa jadi. Aku mungkin mengubah ruang bawah tanah menjadi penjara.
The cup you choose to fill has no bottom.
Cangkir yang kau isi tak berdasar.
It is time to stop this madness.
Sudah saatnya menghentikan kegilaan ini.
Why on earth would I do that?
Kenapa aku harus begitu?
So your parents can rest in peace.
Agar orangtuamu dapat beristirahat dengan damai.
My parents hated me.
Orangtuaku membenci aku.
Do you understand?
Kau mengerti?
They wronged me... and I will make it right.
Mereka menghukum aku... dan aku akan membalasnya.
They loved you.
Mereka mencintaimu.
They loved you so much that having to send you away killed them.
Mereka amat mencintaimu hingga karena mengirimmu pergi, mereka mati.
The dead exist in the past... and I must tend to the future.
Yang mati berada di masa lalu... aku harus mengurus masa depan.
Set the soothsayer free. She's no use to me.
Lepaskan Peramal. Dia tidak berguna bagiku.
Goodbye, Shen. I wish you happiness.
Selamat tinggal, Shen. Semoga kau bahagia.
Happiness must be taken.
Kebahagiaan harus diraih.
And I will take mine.
Dan aku akan meraihnya.
- Hurry it up! - Move it!
Cepatlah!Maju!
If all of those weapons leave the building, China will fall.
Bila semua senjata itu keluar, China akan jatuh.
- We bring down the building. - Hey, guys. How about this?
Hancurkan bangunannya.! Bagaimana jika begini?
- This will work! - All right, let's go.
Itu akan berhasil!) Baiklah, mari pergi.
I can't feel my face.
Aku tak bisa merasakan wajahku.
Did you hear him call it Year of the Peacock?
Kau dengar dia menyebutnya Tahun Burung Merak?
- Hey.
Hei.JHei.
OK. So, keep it cool. Keep it cool. Keep it cool.
Baiklah. Tenang. Tenang. Tenang.
You! Where are you going?
Kalian! Mau ke mana?
On your feet! And wipe those stupid grins off your faces.
Berdiri! Jangan tersenyum konyol.
Move, you dogs! Faster, faster! Load them all!
Bergerak, payah! Lebih cepat, cepat! Masukkan semuanya!
Greetings, panda.
Salam, panda.
- Tell me what happened that night. - What night?
Beritahu yang terjadi malam itu.! Malam apa?
- That night. - Ah, that night.
Malam itu.! Ah, malam itu.
Yes! We're talking about the same night, right?
Ya! Maksud kita, malam yang sama, bukan?
Yes, I was there. Yes. I watched as your parents abandoned you.
Ya, aku ada di sana. Ya. Aku melihat orangtuamu membuangmu.
It's a terrible thing. I believe it went something like this.
Hal yang buruk. Kurasa jalannya seperti ini.
Here's your New Year's gift.
Ini hadiah Tahun Barumu.
Hope you like it, ‘cause you can't return it.
Semoga kau suka, sebab tidak bisa dikembalikan.
Po? What's he doing here?
Po? Sedang apa dia di sini?
Return it! Return it!
Kembalikan! Kembalikan!
Are you willing to die to find the truth?
Kau bersedia mati sebagai ganti kebenaran?
You bet Il am. Although I'd prefer not to.
Pasti. Tapi, sebaiknya tidak.
We got them. Go!
Kami lawan mereka. Pergilah!
You looking for me?
Kau mencari aku?
I said that too soon, didn't I?
Aku bilang terlalu cepat, ya?
Po!
Po!
Po, get away from him.
Po, menyingkir darinya.
I'll get up. Here we go.
Aku akan naik. Ayo.
- No more running, Shen. - So it seems.
Jangan lari lagi, Shen.' Kelihatannya begitu.
Now... answers.
Sekarang... jawablah.
Oh, you want to know so badly.
Oh, kau amat ingin tahu.
You think knowing will heal you, huh?
Kau pikir, kau akan merasa lebih baik, ya?
Fill some crater in your soul?
Jiwamu akan pulih?
Well, here's your answer.
Inilah jawabanmu.
Your parents didn't love you.
Orangtuamu tidak mencintaimu.
But here...
Tapi ini...
...let me heal you!
..biarkan aku memulihkanmu!
No!
Tidak!
Yeah, like you could make me drink that.
Jangan paksa aku minum itu.
If ! wanted you dead, I would have left you in that river.
Kalau aku ingin kau mati, aku tinggalkan saja kau di sungai.
- Well, why save me? - So you can fulfill your destiny.
Kenapa kau menyelamatkan aku?! Agar kau bisa memenuhi takdirmu.
What are you talking about? Where am I?
Kau bicara apa? Di mana ini?
What is this place?
Tempat ini apa?
I'm surprised you remember so little.
Aku heran, ingatanmu hanya sedikit.
But you were so little when it happened.
Tapi kau masih kecil saat itu terjadi.
Perhaps you do remember.
Mungkin kau ingat.
What? It's just a stupid nightmare.
Apa? Itu hanya mimpi buruk.
Nightmare? Or memory?
Mimpi buruk? Atau ingatan?
This was a thriving village.
Desa itu makmur.
Young Shen was in line to rule Gongmen City.
Shen muda akan mewarisi kuasa akan Kota Gongmen.
But he wanted more.
Tapi dia ingin lebih banyak.
I foretold that someone would stand in his way. A panda.
Aku meramal, ada penghalangnya. Seekor panda.
But I never could have foretold what came next.
Tapi aku tak bisa meramal yang terjadi selanjutnya.
Get them all!
Tangkap mereka semua!
Take our son and run away! Go!
Bawa putra kita dan lari! Pergi!
Stop fighting. Let it flow.
Jangan melawannya. Terimalah.
Your story may not have such a happy beginning,
Kisahmu mungkin tidak berawal baik,
but that doesn't make you who you are.
tapi itu tidak menetapkan jati dirimu.
It is the rest of your story.
Yang penting, kisahmu selanjutnya.
Who you choose to be.
Kau memilih menjadi apa.
So, who are you, panda?
Siapakah kau, panda?
lam Po.
Aku Po.
And I'm gonna need a hat.
Dan aku perlu topi.
Such sad, sad faces.
Wajah-wajah yang sedih.
But now is a time only for joy.
Tapi sekarang saatnya bersukacita.
You are going to be part of something beautiful.
Kalian akan menjadi bagian dari sesuatu yang indah.
Once we reach the harbor, in front of all the world,
Setelah mencapai pelabuhan, di hadapan seluruh dunia,
you and your precious kung fu will die.
kalian dan kung fu yang berharga akan mati.
Then China will know to bow before me.
Lalu China akan takluk padaku.
Set sail!
Berlayar!
What is that?
Apa itu?
Honestly, guys, I never thought I'd die like this.
Sejujurnya, aku tak mengira akan mati seperti ini.
l always thought I'd meet a nice girl and settle down and...
Kukira aku akan bertemu gadis yang baik, menikah dan...
..then she'd eat my head.
lalu dia akan makan kepalaku.
- So sad. - We cannot give up hope.
Sedih sekali.! Jangan menyerah.
Po would want us to remain strong. Hard-core. Right, Tigress?
Po ingin kita tegar. Tangguh. Benar, Macan?
- Lord Shen, what about the bridge? - Nothing stands in my way.
Raja Shen, jembatannya?! Tidak ada yang bisa menghalangi aku.
Fire!
Tembak!
You coward!
Pengecut!
Po?
Po?
How many times do! have to kill the same stinking panda?
Berapa kali aku harus membunuh panda yang sama?
Shen!
Shen!
A panda stands between you and your destiny.
Seekor panda menghalangi kau dan takdirmu.
What?
Apa?
Prepare yourself for a hot serving of justice.
Bersiaplah menghadapi keadilan.
Your reign of terror comes to an end.
Terormu telah selesai.
- What? - And now, free the Five!
Apa?! Sekarang, bebaskan para pendekar!
Disc of Destruction!
Piring Penghancur!
OK. Take aim!
Baiklah. Bidik!
Ready?
Siap?
You can't follow me.
Kalian tidak bisa mengikuti aku.
Just get him!
Tembak saja!
- Yeah. Here we go. - Come on!
Ya. Ke sini.!Ayo!
- No, no, no, don't shoot! - Don't shoot!
Jangan tembak!! Jangan tembak!
No, don't shoot!
Tidak, jangan tembak!
- You don't shoot! - 1 won't shoot if you won't shoot.
Tidak, bila kau juga tidak.
Yeah!
Ya!
- Don't shoot! Cross fire! - Attack!
Jangan tembak! Perang!! Serang!
- Catch of Freedom! - Monkey!
Lemparan Kebebasan!!Monyet!
Impressive, Dragon Warrior. What's your plan?
Mengagumkan, Pendekar Naga. Apa rencanamu?
- Step one, free the Five. - What's step two?
Tahap satu, bebaskan para pendekar.! Tahap dua?
Honestly, I didn't think I'd make it this far.
Aku tak kira berhasil sejauh ini.
Po!
Po!
Stop Shen before he gets to the harbor.
Hentikan Shen sebelum sampai di pelabuhan.
Nice!
Bagus!
Viper, Puppet of Death!
Ular, Boneka Kematian!
Tigress!
Macan!
- Master Ox! - Jump!
Guru Lembu!)Lompat!
- And Croc! - Vengeance is served.
Dan Buaya!! Balas dendam terlampiaskan.
- Why did you...? - Your friend there is very persuasive.
Kenapa kalian...?! Temanmu amat meyakinkan.
Master Shifu!
Guru Shifu!
Quickly. Use their boats to block the way.
Cepat. Gunakan perahu untuk menghalangi.
Crane!
Bangau!
Wings of Justice!
Sayap Keadilan!
Yeah!
Ya!
What?
Apa?
I love you guys.
Aku sayang kalian semua.
Why aren't we firing?
Kenapa kita tidak menembak?
They're taking out our gunners, sir. They're getting close.
Mereka melumpuhkan penembak kita, tuan. Mereka sudah dekat.
Fire! Fire at them!
Tembak! Tembak mereka!
- But, sir, we'll kill our own. - I said fire at them!
Tapi, tuan, akan membunuh prajurit kita.!Aku bilang, tembak!
Fire!
Tembak!
No.
Tidak.
Po!
Po!
Tigress?
Macan?
As you wish.
Seperti keinginanmu.
Let's finish this.
Mari kita akhiri ini.
Fire!
Tembak!
Inner peace.
Kedamaian jiwa.
Again!
Lagi!
Yeah!
Ya!
Kill him! Somebody kill him!
Bunuh dia! Siapa saja!
What? No. No!
Apa? Tidak. Tidak!
Keep firing! Keep firing!
Terus menembak! Terus menembak!
Skadoosh.
Skadoosh.
How did you...?
Bagaimana kau...?
How did you do it?
Bagaimana kau melakukannya?
You know, you just keep your elbows up and keep the shoulders loose.
Hanya perlu menaikkan siku dan melemaskan bahu.
Not that. How did you find peace?
Bukan. Bagaimana cara mendapat kedamaian jiwa?
I took away your parents. Everything.
Aku merebut orangtuamu. Semuanya.
I scarred you for life.
Aku menggores hidupmu.
See, that's the thing, Shen. Scars heal.
Itulah, Shen. Goresan bisa sembuh.
No, they don't. Wounds heal.
Tidak. Yang sembuh ialah luka.
Oh, yeah. What do scars do? They fade, I guess?
Oh, ya. Goresan memudar, ya?
- 1 don't care what scars do. - You should, Shen.
Aku tak peduli.! Kau harus peduli, Shen.
You gotta let go of that stuff from the past, ‘cause it just doesn't matter.
Lepaskan masa lalumu, sebab tak ada gunanya.
The only thing that matters is what you choose to be now.
Yang penting ialah apa yang kau pilih sekarang.
You're right.
Kau benar.
Then I choose... this!
Aku memilih... ini!
That was pretty hard-core.
Kau cukup tangguh.
- Po! - You did it!
Po!Kau berhasil!
- Come here! Yeah! - Don't ever do that again, please.
Kemarilah! Ya!) Jangan ulangi lagi.
It seems you have found inner peace.
Kelihatannya, kau menemukan kedamaian jiwa.
And at such a young age.
Di usia yang amat muda.
Well, I had a pretty good teacher.
Ya, guruku cukup bagus.
What do you mean he's not here? It's my son's birthday.
Apa maksudmu, dia tidak di sini? Hari ini ulang tahun putraku.
All he wanted was to meet the Dragon Warrior.
Dia hanya ingin bertemu Pendekar Naga.
How about some tofu birthday cake instead, huh?
Kau ingin kue ulang tahun dari tahu?
You know, I think we'll just try again another time.
Kurasa kami akan datang lagi lain kali.
When do you think he'll be back?
Kapan dia akan kembali?
I don't know. OK, I don't know. Maybe never.
Aku tak tahu. Mungkin, dia takkan kembali.
I mean, I worry, OK? But that's my job, I'm his dad.
Aku khawatir, tahu? Tapi itu wajar, aku ayahnya.
At least, l was his dad.
Setidaknya, dulu.
Why did he have to go and save China? I know why.
Kenapa dia harus menyelam atkan China? Aku tahu kenapa.
But why? He's just one little panda.
Tapi kenapa? Dia hanya panda kecil.
So, how did it go? Did you save China?
Jadi, bagaimana? Kau menyelamatkan China?
Yep.
Ya.
Well, knew you would.
Aku sudah tahu itu.
That's why I had new signs made.
Sebab itu, aku membuat promosi baru.
“My son saved China. You, too, can save.
“Putraku menyelamatkan China. Berhematlah.
Buy one dumpling, get one free.”
Beli satu kue bola, dapatkan satu gratis."
Hey, that's a pretty good deal.
Hei, itu tawaran menarik.
- Would you like to try one? - Maybe later.
Kau ingin mencoba satu?! Nanti saja.
There's something I should tell you.
Aku harus mengatakan sesuatu.
While I was gone, I found the village where I was born.
Saat aku pergi, aku menemukan desa kelahiranku.
I found out how I ended up in that radish basket.
Aku tahu kenapa aku ditaruh di keranjang radis itu.
You did?
Sungguh?
- 1 know who lam. - You do?
Aku tahu jati diriku.! Benar?
I'm your son.
Aku putramu.
Il love you, Dad.
Aku sayang padamu, Ayah.
Il love you, too, son.
Aku sayang padamu juga, nak.
Delicious, fat radishes!
Radis gemuk yang lezat!
You're probably hungry. Let me make you something to eat.
Kau mungkin lapar. Biar aku siapkan makanan.
What are you talking about? I'll cook.
Apa maksudmu? Aku akan masak.
- No, no, I'll cook. - Dad!
Tidak, biar aku saja.!Ayah!
Well, it's the least I can do. You saved China.
Aku ingin. Kau telah menyelamatkan China.
No, it's the least I can do. You raised me.
Tidak, aku ingin. Kau telah membesarkan aku.
- Po. - Dad.
Po.Ayah.
- Po! - OK.
Po!jBaiklah.
Let's both cook. Together.
Mari kita masak. Bersama.
Together.
Bersama.
No, I'll cook.
Tidak, aku akan masak.
My son is alive.
Putraku masih hidup.
ENGLISH ESL
INDONESIAN